



http://fredevery.co.za

fred@fredevery.co.za +27 74 155 0016

> 7 Webber Street Grahamstown Eastern Cape 6139 South Africa

Fred is a self-taught, passionate web developer, designer, entrepreneur, and, according to his young sons, overall super hero.

His main area of specialization is in Frontend Development, having spent years honing his craft through taking on various projects, and undergoing personal professional development at every given opportunity.

EDUCATION

RHODES UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Fine Arts (B.F.A.), Photography 2002-2005

ST. STITHIANS COLLEGE *Matric* 1998-2001

INTERESTS

My three sons, My wife, Programming, Design, Video & Filmography, Scriptwriting, Writing Music, Listening to Music, Playing Guitar, Playing the Recorder with my sons, Reading, Cycling, Rock climbing, Wakeboarding, Paddleskiing, Surfing.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES

JavaScript, CSS 2/3, HTML 4/5, CoffeeScript, SASS/SCSS, Ruby, PHP, Bash, SQL

PARADIGMS

Design Patterns, Responsive Web Development, Responsive HTML Emails, Agile Development, Application Architecture, Rapid Prototyping, MVC/MVP/MVVM, AJAX, REST, Object Oriented Programming, Test Driven Development, Behaviour Driven Development, Event Driven Programming, Continuous Integration, Graceful Degradation, Progressive Enhancement, SEO, Templating, Load Balancing, CDN

FRAMEWORKS

Meteor, Backbone.js, Marionette.js, Famous, Ruby on Rails, PhoneGap, Compass, Bootstrap, Wordpress, Node.js, Jasmine

LIBRARIES / APIS

jQuery.js, Stamp{it}, Underscore.js, Paper.js, Kinetic.js, MooTools, Modernizr, Handlebars, Moment.js, Google Analytics, Google Maps, ImageMagick, Phantom.js, Isotope/Masonry

STORAGE

MongoDB, MySQL

HTTP SERVERS

Apache2, Nginx

PLATFORMS CODE VERSIONING

OS X, Ubuntu, Windows, Android, iOS Git, SVN

SOFTWARE

Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe InDesign, Sketch

COMMS

Slack, Trello, Skype, Google Hangout, Google Chat

EXPERIENCE

AUDIOADDICT, Inc. - (Dec 2013 - Nov 2015)

Frontend Developer (Remote/Telecommute)

Frontend developer part of a small, incredibly talented, team. Helped to maintain the code bases for 4 different network sites. Overhauled the Premium sell page, which included a re-write of the the frontend portion of the payment processing system. Adapted the calendar view to work with the updated Backbone/Marionette driven flagship network (Di.fm). Re-wrote the member settings area for Di.fm. Re-worked the HTML email templates for Di.fm to be responsive. Reskinned all 3 of the existing networks (JazzRadio.com, RockRadio.com, RadioTunes.com), and skinned the upcoming network (ClassicalRadio.com).

HEALTHTAP, Inc. - (Oct 2010 - Nov 2013)

Lead Frontend Developer (Remote/Telecommute)

Sole frontend developer during the early stages of the start up. Implemented initial version of the web application as a multipage app using Mootools. Led the rework of the initial application into a single page app using Backbone. Implemented an asset packaging strategy, including a build script written in bash. Core developer on tablet version of the web application packaged with PhoneGap. Developed an automated porting task in rake to port web application code into tablet optimised code. Core developer on an automated build script.

TOPTAL, LLC. - (Sep 2009 - Jun 2011)

Frontend Developer (Remote/Telecommute)

One of the first frontend developers to be brought on board at the beginning of the platform. Worked on some internal projects before being assigned to a project for Ford through the IDEO design agency. My last project with the company was with HealthTap, Inc.

IMAGINET ISP - (Jun 2006 - Dec 2009)

Lead Frontend Developer

Designed, coded, deployed and maintained online presence for the company which allowed them to sell services. Led the marketing team and designed digital adverts, print adverts, letterheads, the logo and signage. Designed, coded, deployed and maintained a customer control panel that gives users dedicated controls over their hosting, domain, ADSL and email services provided by the company. Designed, coded, deployed and maintained a simple browser based website bulder.

